[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 37]
You can't provide me with
a peaceful and carefree home,
nor do you understand how to put your husband first.
You're so competitive,
always trying to stand out.
You're not the right person
to spend the rest of my life with.
What did you say?
Is that really how you think of me?
Do you really think
you're a good wife?
Your mind is always on the cases,
and your eyes are always on the files.
Have you ever seriously
thought about
what kind of wife a man wants?
You were a substitute bride to begin with,
carrying the identity of a spy.
Don't forget the three delusions.
The three-month period has passed.
I, Shen Du,
am determined to divorce you.
If that's the case,
then let's divorce.
From today on, I, Yan Xing,
and you, Shen Du, will go
our separate ways.
Everything related to White Ghost
have nothing to do with me anymore.
The honor and disgrace of your Shen family
will no longer concern me!
♫My heart burned, leaving me cold and forlorn♫
♫And a lifetime of loneliness♫
♫My love blazed. Where did it scatter♫
♫And where did it leave its marks?♫
♫Drifting through the mist♫
♫Amidst the vast, endless waves, I searched in the darkness♫
♫You passed by, igniting fireworks♫
♫For the sake of an end, I embraced silence and became a Shura♫
♫Love is elusive, piercing you and burning me♫
♫Along the way, flowers bloom and fall, rain pours heavily♫
♫Lights will cross♫
♫You are my destination♫
♫Who will save me from my loneliness and confusion?♫
♫Understanding my fragility, no words are needed♫
♫Who will save me from my panic and obsession?♫
♫Sheltering my solitude, never letting me fall♫
♫The chains of fate between us cannot be broken♫
♫Holding the warmth you once gave♫
♫Guiding me to see myself, the person I truly am♫
♫Who will save me from right and wrong?♫
♫Tossed in the sea of people, just hold me tight♫
♫Who will save me from grudges and karma?♫
♫Healing my sorrow, never letting me escape♫
♫The past fades, how many times have we met?♫
♫Who can break free from destiny?♫
♫I'll cross rivers and leap into fire for you♫
♫I'm willing to disappear with you in the hustle and bustle♫
Xing.
What's wrong?
You look so pale.
What happened?
Mother.
Xing.
Xing. Xing.
Shen Du!
Shen Du.
Xing.
You're awake.
Your high fever
really scared me.
Where are you going?
I'm going to find Shen Du.
You mustn't!
Why are you still looking for that jerk?
You braved the snow to plead his innocence,
but what about him?
He's just been released.
He didn't care about your illness,
and...
And what?
What's wrong with your voice?
And he brought a divorce paper.
Mother,
where's the divorce paper?
Where's the divorce paper, Mother?
Where's the divorce paper?
Mother.
I still can't believe it.
Grand Commander Shen usually seems
so upright and incorruptible.
How could he
openly side with the Black Rakshasa?
Shen Du has led the Imperial Security Bureau
and arrested many officials who haven't joined Lai Luozhi
for the Imperial Investigation Department
these past few days.
The Imperial Security Bureau has now
completely degraded into
the Imperial Investigation Department's watchdog.
Since he's made that choice,
our Yan family...
Mojie,
since Shen Du
has sent the divorce paper,
no matter what he does
in the future,
it will have nothing to do
with our Yan family anymore.
Given the current situation, divorce
might not be a bad thing for the Yan family
to stay away from the conflicts.
But I'm afraid Xing
will be heartbroken.
[Changmo Pavilion]
There's even more
making her heartbroken.
Those who have always been close to her,
that Constable Marshal
and Miss Yun Que,
were killed by the Imperial Investigation Department
on the night
they helped her appeal in the palace.
Xing.
Xu and Yun Que...
are dead?
Xing.
Your fever just broke.
Are you trying to kill yourself?
[Grave of Constable Marshal Xu Xiangren and Miss Yun Que]
Xu.
Yun Que.
I'm the one who got you killed.
I'm so sorry.
Even without you,
they would have died anyway.
Shen Du.
Don't blame
their deaths on yourself.
You're not that important.
Xu Xiangren wanted to investigate
evidence of Lord Lai's treason.
So he had to die.
You really have sided with Lai Luozhi?
The night Xu and Yun Que died,
you were released.
You really...
Shen Du,
what's wrong with you?
Have you forgotten your ambitions?
Have you forgotten the Shen family's old case
and those dozens of innocent people
who died unjustly?
I came here today
to advise you not to complicate things further.
Think about the Yan family.
Sign the divorce paper.
[Yan]
[Divorce Agreement Yan Xing]
With your blood,
we're divorced.
For Xu and Yun Que,
for all those who died unjustly,
Shen Du,
from now on, you and I
are strangers.
[Grave of Constable Marshal Xu Xiangren and Miss Yun Que]
Xing.
What happened to you?
We went to the Yan's Mansion.
Ms. Jin said you weren't home.
Jiang Langxing and I
hurried over to find you.
You've been to the cemetery?
Xu and Yun Que
died because of me.
Xing.
Don't say that.
The reason Lai Luozhi hated Commander Xu
is also because he saved me.
But I left.
Commander Xu and Yun Que,
they passed away peacefully.
I think...
they must be
happy in heaven.
You're hurt?
Shen Du has made up his mind
to join forces with Lai Luozhi.
White Ghost
has really teamed up with Lai Luozhi?
He is no longer
the Shen Du I once knew.
From now on,
I will have nothing to do with him.
Xing.
[Shen's Mansion]
If you're worried about Xing,
why don't you go talk to her?
I know my own daughter.
Xing has always been independent and strong-willed.
When facing such a big issue,
if we approach her rashly,
she will definitely
try to ease our concerns
by forcing a smile
and hiding her feelings.
Indeed,
Xing never lets anyone worry about her.
Women,
above all, should not suppress their grievances
and sorrows.
It will make them sick.
Let her be alone for a while.
♫I hope you also look up and see the radiant stars and moon♫
You can sleep there
tonight.
If you want to stay,
there's still half the space inside.
♫No matter how vast the world is, I'll wait for your appearance♫
You sleep on the inside.
♫A quick glance at each other♫
♫Has warmed the winter in memories♫
♫Don't mind the destined solitude, and shine brightly♫
She became my wife
♫I'll wait until the years blossom like flowers♫
as if it were predestined.
♫The ice and snow slowly melted♫
I want to tell her
that in my heart,
she has always been the one,
♫I heard those tender words♫
from the very beginning.
♫He told her, "I love you"♫
You can't provide me with
a peaceful and carefree home,
♫What I saw in my dreams♫
nor do you understand how to put your husband first.
You're so competitive,
♫Is not a flashy illusion♫
always trying to stand out.
You're not the right person
to spend the rest of my life with.
♫I don't fear the challenges ahead, riding a white horse to chase after time♫
The three-month period has passed.
I, Shen Du,
♫Let's go together♫
am determined to divorce you.
♫Love is pure and flawless, indifferent to the changes of the world♫
♫Let's experience it together♫
Haven't she eaten yet?
Not a bite,
and no medicine either.
She won't bandage the wound on her hand.
She won't even open the door.
What should we do?
I've just gotten divorced too.
Lately, I've been eating well and sleeping soundly.
Life is much more enjoyable than before.
How about
I go and try to persuade her?
Good idea.
Father!
Father, bad news.
I just went to buy dried fruits for Xing
and saw people from the Imperial Investigation Department
all around our mansion.
Are you sure it's the Imperial Investigation Department?
I've been in the Imperial Security Bureau for so long.
I can recognize these
undercover agents and informants.
Our mansion is being
watched by the Imperial Investigation Department.
This is a disaster.
A disaster.
In all my years as an official,
I've never seen anything like this.
The court situation is unpredictable now.
Lai Luozhi has too much power.
Shen Du just divorced Xing
and immediately joined Lai Luozhi.
What does this mean?
What does it mean?
It means
trouble for our Yan family.
[Cangming Hall]
Your Majesty,
with the beginning of spring approaching,
the annual Grand Court Assembly
is about to start preparations.
This is the draft protocol
based on previous years' procedures,
prepared by the Ministry of Personnel and the Ministry of Rites.
At that time, officials from various regions
and military leaders from different garrisons
will return to Xiang'an to pay their respects and report on their duties.
However,
Since Your Majesty's ascension,
the Grand Court Assembly
has always been held
on the second day of the second lunar month, during spring plowing.
But this year,
the Grand Empress Dowager is in poor health.
Should the Grand Astrologer select another auspicious date?
The Grand Court Assembly
is a significant event
for determining state affairs
and involves officials and border generals
coming to the capital.
It should not be postponed lightly.
Let's stick to the original date.
If the Grand Empress Dowager
is still unwell by then,
I will accompany
His Majesty
to host the Grand Court Assembly.
Lord Lai,
are you really going to
host the Grand Court Assembly
on behalf of the Grand Empress Dowager?
Why not?
Lord Lai,
the Grand Court Assembly
is an annual grand event for all officials,
showcasing the imperial majesty
and royal dignity.
The Grand Empress Dowager's regency
is to perform the duties on behalf of His Majesty.
You?
By what right?
By the Grand Empress Dowager's trust in me.
By her entrusting me with the duty of
overseeing all officials.
I must shoulder
the responsibility for many court affairs.
I believe
His Majesty would also be willing
for me to accompany him
in hosting the Grand Court Assembly
and meeting officials and generals.
His Majesty is
inviting Lord Lai.
During the Grand Court Assembly,
His Majesty clearly wants Lord Lai
by his side.
Indeed.
The Grand Empress Dowager has authorized Lord Lai
to oversee all officials.
It's legitimate for him
to host the Grand Court Assembly.
It's legitimate for Lord Lai
You bunch of rats!
You're shameless, distorting the truth!
And you,
Lai Luozhi,
you're overstepping your bounds!
Your intention to usurp power is obvious!
You must be punished!
Grand Commander Shen,
you haven't said a word today.
Why don't you say something?
Insulting a high-ranking official without reason in court,
according to the laws of the Imperial Security Bureau,
is there a provision for this?
Anyone insulting high officials in court
should be imprisoned in the Imperial Security Bureau's dungeon
and punished by water torture.
Alright,
let it be so.
Shen Du, you...
Grand Commander Shen,
when did you
become a follower of Lai?
Minister Zhang.
Princess Ying.
You seem to be
quite dissatisfied with me.
Are you afraid
I'll expose your
dirty secrets?
What nonsense are you talking about?
Princess Ying
and Minister Zhang
are colluding with rebels in Gannan Area,
plotting treachery!
Lai Luozhi,
don't you dare slander me.
Lai Luozhi.
Lord Lai,
you've always
oppressed officials who oppose you.
Now
it's finally my turn.
But everything needs evidence.
In broad daylight,
you're not allowed
to distort the truth!
Evidence?
Of course there's evidence.
I obtained from the Imperial Security Bureau
the records previously submitted by
the criminal official Mo Qianzhi.
Every detail is clearly recorded,
leaving no room for your arguments.
You--
Isn't that right, Grand Commander Shen?
According to Mo Qianzhi's previous confession,
Princess Ying colluded with the Gannan garrison.
Minister Zhang allowed his subordinates
to embezzle funds from Gannan.
They should be confined to their residences
for thorough investigation.
I won't
tolerate such recklessness!
Where are the Qianniu Guards?
Your Highness,
can't you see it now?
Most of the court already
belongs to the Lai faction now!
With your positions,
it's better for you
to leave gracefully.
Do I need to send
the Imperial Investigation Department and the Imperial Security Bureau
to arrest you?
Shen Du, you traitor!
You're in cahoots with the Black Rakshasa!
You
lawless
traitorous rebels
will die in pain!
Die in pain!
Unexpectedly,
I've always been devoted,
yet still unable to repay
the kindness of His Majesty and the Grand Empress Dowager.
But these ignorant fools
twist my intentions so.
Now, with such a heavy responsibility on my shoulders,
I can only do my utmost to serve loyally
until death.
Who cares about my reputation in life or after death?
Isn't that right,
Grand Commander Shen?
Well then,
prepare the Grand Court Assembly
as we discussed earlier.
What are you doing?
You lowly commoners
dare to come here?
You're disgracing
the Hongwen Academy.
We must thoroughly clean it.
I
entered the Hongwen Academy
fair and square through the entrance exam.
Knowledge knows no class distinctions.
Why do you bully commoners?
You're nothing but
a dog let in
through the door.
Do you really think
you can be on equal footing with us nobles?
Remember this,
even if a dog enters the house,
it's still just a dog.
Well, Lord Lai
doesn't have any noble background either.
Yet you nobles
are all happy
to flatter and serve him
like dogs, aren't you?
How dare you!
Beat him up!
Stop!
Guard Jing,
these noble students
are ganging up on the commoners.
Hongwen Academy
is the highest institution of learning in Cang State,
directly under the Emperor's Imperial College.
Instead of focusing on your studies,
you're making a ruckus and fighting here.
What a disgrace!
I...
It was them.
Yes.
It's him.
He's the one stirring up trouble.
He's been disrupting our studies.
Yes, yes, it's him.
He's the one stirring up trouble.
Guard Jing.
No, it's not.
It's them.
Since you're disrupting
so many students here,
you'll be sent to the Imperial Security Bureau's prison
to reflect on your actions.
How did
the Imperial Security Bureau become like this?
Are you truly siding with the traitor?
It was Grand Commander Shen
who escorted us here to take the exams.
He said the Hongwen Academy
would recruit talents regardless of their background.
Now,
are you telling me
that we, students from humble backgrounds,
who have studied so hard,
were wrong?
Being insensible
and having no sense of propriety—
that's what's wrong.
Take him away.
You dare to fight against us?
That's right.
Serves him right.
Move aside! Move aside!
Get out of the way!
People call us
the Black and White Rakshasas.
Now that we're riding
in this world together,
it's quite an interesting experience.
On such a spacious street,
can't you people from the Imperial Investigation Department
even walk properly?
Must you charge around recklessly,
bullying the common people?
Letting random people
hinder His Lordship's inspection—
are you performing your duty?
Our duty as constables
is to protect the capital
and ensure the safety of the people,
not to be anyone's road-clearing servants.
They're truly an eyesore.
Grand Commander Shen,
the capital's security is the Imperial Security Bureau's responsibility.
These petty troublemakers
don't need
to be in the city, causing a nuisance.
Indeed.
Shen Du,
how can you be so blind to right and wrong,
aiding and abetting tyranny?
How can you face
the deceased Commander Xu and Yun Que?
How can you face Yan Xing?
A mere constable
dares to challenge the Grand Commander?
It seems you haven't tasted
the Imperial Investigation Department's punishment yet.
Guards!
Wait.
Since he insulted me,
let me
handle it myself.
I'm sparing your life today,
so you can go back
and keep your brothers in check.
Tell your friends
that any past
favors are
all gone now.
If you dare to speak out of turn again,
I'll make sure you beg for life
and wish you were dead.
[Ministry of Justice]
Chuichui.
Jiang Langxing was humiliated
by White Ghost in public.
What?
[Just Rewards and Punishments]
Shen Du publicly humiliated Jiang Langxing?
Yes,
that's what I heard.
It's because he and the constables
offended Lord Lai.
Shen Du.
So,
he's joined Lai Luozhi?
The Black and White Rakshasas
have united, huh?
Shen Du...
I'd like to see
if he has any conscience left.
Where is the Director of the Ministry of Justice?
[Just Rewards and Punishments]
Let go of me.
Go quickly.
Behave yourself.
Lord Lai, what brings you to
the Ministry of Justice today?
Lord Lai.
Nerd Jiang.
I'm fine.
I received a complaint
that the records in the Ministry of Justice are incomplete
and full of loopholes.
Who's responsible for this?
It's...
So it's Secretary Lu.
Well,
what a coincidence.
Who dared to complain about
the Ministry of Justice?
Don't they know that Secretary Lu
is my woman?
Drag him out!
Yes.
If anyone
dares to bother Secretary Lu again,
they will be going against me.
Chuichui,
rest assured.
No matter where you go,
you're still my woman.
No way!
Is that so?
Lai Luozhi.
You thief!
Let me go!
If you have the guts, let's fight to the death!
You, who have been
crushed under my feet like an ant,
dare to negotiate with me?
Do you even deserve it?
Lai Luozhi,
what exactly do you want?
What?
Feeling sorry for him?
You actually shed tears
for such an insignificant ant.
I feel bad for you.
Actually,
I really don't want to make things difficult for you.
However, I couldn't sleep last night
and thought of
that folk song you once sang.
Why don't you sing it for me again?
Maybe if I'm in a better mood,
I'll be willing
to show some mercy.
Chuichui,
don't listen to him.
Don't sing.
Shut up!
♫Speak not in vain♫
♫The old lady scolds♫
♫Mother picks flowers endlessly♫
♫Speak not in vain♫
Be a good boy, Luozhi.
♫The old lady scolds♫
♫Mother picks flowers endlessly♫
I've said before,
as long as you don't leave me,
you can have whatever
you want.
As for those people you care about,
for your sake,
I won't be too hard on them.